hdrsoft.com 2018-11-24

# HDRsoft Privacy Policy

## What information does HDRsoft collect?

At HDRsoft we use your data very sparingly. We believe in putting customers first, not our bottom line.

Unlike many companies, we don't track users and collect as much information as we can. We aim to gather and use only the information we need to serve you.

HDRsoft collects information from you when:

  * you purchase a license for our software
  * you contact our email support
  * you contact our live chat support
  * you subscribe to the Photomatix announcements list or newsletter
  * you participate in our contests

When you purchase a license for our software, HDRsoft collects the information you submitted to complete the purchase, which includes your email address and name.

When you purchase by credit card or online banking, the information is provided by our e-commerce reseller partner who processed your order (FastSpring or BlueSnap), and is covered by their respective privacy policies ([FastSpring](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) privacy policy, [BlueSnap](https://home.bluesnap.com/privacy-policy/) privacy policy). The information they provide us with does _not_ include any credit card or bank information.

When you purchase via PayPal, the information HDRsoft collects is provided by PayPal and covered by [PayPal's privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). We also collect the country of the identifier associated with your computer or network (IP address) for PayPal purchases in order to comply with our VAT obligations with EU tax authorities.

When you contact our email support, we log the email you send us in our helpdesk system, which includes your email address.

When you contact our live chat support, you are using the system of our partner Live Person, and the information they collect is covered in their [privacy policy](https://www.liveperson.com/policies/privacy).

When you subscribe to Photomatix announcements or our newsletter, we collect the information in the form you submitted when you clicked on the 'Subscribe' button. 

When you participate in one of our contests, we collect information in the form you submitted, and the images you uploaded when you entered the contest. 

## What does HDRsoft use your information for?

  * HDRsoft never sells, shares or transfers your personal information to outside parties, except as required by law.
  * HDRsoft does not collect or store credit card information. All credit card processing is done by our e-commerce reseller partners.
  * The information we collect on you is stored on HDRsoft dedicated servers, with security controls to ensure it is accessible only to people who need this access to support you.

### Email address

HDRsoft uses your email address only for the specific purpose for which you gave it to us.

We do not contact you except in response to your support request, or to send notifications or newsletters to which you have explicitly subscribed, or notifications of awards for contests in which you explicitly participated. You can unsubscribe from any notification or newsletter at any time using the link at the bottom of each message.

When you purchase a license for our software, we only use your email address to send your license information, or to retrieve information if you contact our support to request details related to your purchase. 

We do **not** use your email address to notify you of updates on the software you purchased. If you want to be notified of updates, you need to explicitly authorize us to do so by subscribing to Photomatix [announcements](https://www.hdrsoft.com/subscribe).

### Customer service information

When you contact HDRsoft customer service or technical support, we use details you give us about your system and software, or images you send us, only to provide you with support. We may also use them internally for testing and product improvement purposes.

We do not use them for any other purpose unless you give us explicit permission to use them in some other way.

## Does HDRsoft use cookies?

Cookies are small pieces of information that a website transmits to your web browser (if you allow it) which are stored on your computer. This information allows the website to recognise you when you return.

We only use cookies when you visit one of these two pages of the HDRsoft.com website: 

  * [Purchase page](https://www.hdrsoft.com/order.php): we use cookies to calculate affiliate partner commissions when you purchase a license for our software after visiting the website of an affiliate partner. No personally identifiable information is stored in the cookies.
  * [Main support page](https://www.hdrsoft.com/support/index.html): When you use our live chat support, we store cookies required by our partner LivePerson to provide their live chat support service. The way LivePerson uses cookies is detailed in their [privacy policy](https://www.liveperson.com/policies/privacy#_Toc465674443).

## Contacting us on your data protection

You are welcome to contact us for any question on our privacy policy, or if you want to delete a purchase record we have on you or other information. Please send your query to [support@hdrsoft.com](mailto:support@hdrsoft.com).
